<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<osis xmlns="http://www.bibletechnologies.net/2003/OSIS/namespace" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.bibletechnologies.net/2003/OSIS/namespace http://www.bibletechnologies.net/osisCore.2.1.1.xsd">
<osisText osisRefWork="Bible" xml:lang="und" osisIDWork="Bible.Thomson">
<header>
<work osisWork="Bible.Thomson"/>
</header>
<div type="book" osisID="Hab">
<!-- id comment - Thomson Septuagint -->
<title type="runningHead">Habakkuk</title>
<title level="1" type="main">Ambakum</title>
<title level="3" type="main">or Habakkuk</title>
<title level="2" type="main">ΑΜΒΑΚΟΥΜ</title>
<chapter osisID="Hab.1" sID="Hab.1"/>
<p type="x-embedded">
<verse osisID="Hab.1.1" sID="Hab.1.1"/>The vision which Ambakum the prophet saw.</p>
<p>
<speaker>Ambakum</speaker><verse eID="Hab.1.1"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.1.2" sID="Hab.1.2"/>How long, O Lord shall I cry, and thou not hearken? How long shall I being injured cry to thee, and thou not save?<verse eID="Hab.1.2"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.1.3" sID="Hab.1.3"/>Why hast thou pointed out to me to behold labours and sorrows, misery and impiety? A suit is instituted against me and the judge receiveth
<transChange type="added">bribes</transChange><verse eID="Hab.1.3"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.1.4" sID="Hab.1.4"/>therefore law is disregarded and the cause is not brought to an issue. Because a wicked man oppresseth the just, therefore wrong judgment will be given.</p>
<p>
<speaker>Jehovah</speaker><verse eID="Hab.1.4"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.1.5" sID="Hab.1.5"/>See ye despisers! and view intently and be amazed at wonderful things and vanish. For in your days I am doing a work which you will not believe though one tell you.<verse eID="Hab.1.5"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.1.6" sID="Hab.1.6"/>For lo! I am raising up the Chaldeans that bitter and hasty nation, which marcheth over the breadth of the earth, to possess dwellings which belong not to them.<verse eID="Hab.1.6"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.1.7" sID="Hab.1.7"/>He is terrible and illustrious; his judgment will be from himself, and from himself his prophesy will proceed.<verse eID="Hab.1.7"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.1.8" sID="Hab.1.8"/>His horses can out leap leopards and are swifter than the lynxes of Arabia. When his horsemen have mounted, they will rush impetuously from afar, and will fly like an eagle, eager for prey.<verse eID="Hab.1.8"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.1.9" sID="Hab.1.9"/>Destruction will come on the wicked who set themselves against him; and he will gather captives like the sand.<verse eID="Hab.1.9"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.1.10" sID="Hab.1.10"/>He indeed will riot in kings; and petty princes will be his scorn. Of every fortress he will make a scoff and will raise a mount and take it.<verse eID="Hab.1.10"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.1.11" sID="Hab.1.11"/>Then he will change his mind and depart and be pacified.</p>
<p>
<speaker>Ambakum</speaker><verse eID="Hab.1.11"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.1.12" sID="Hab.1.12"/>This is the majesty which belongeth to my God. Art not thou from everlasting? Lord, my God, my Holy One! let us not die. Thou, Lord, hast appointed this for judgment: and formed it that its correction may work conviction in me.<verse eID="Hab.1.12"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.1.13" sID="Hab.1.13"/>Thine eye is too pure to behold wicked deeds, or to look on the labours of sorrow. Why lookest thou upon despisers? Wilt thou be silent when the wicked
swallow up the righteous?<verse eID="Hab.1.13"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.1.14" sID="Hab.1.14"/>Wilt thou make these men like the fishes of the sea, and like those reptiles which have no leader?<verse eID="Hab.1.14"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.1.15" sID="Hab.1.15"/>He hath drawn up destruction with a hook, and hath dragged out one with a dredge, and enclosed another with his sweep net. For this cause he will rejoice and his heart will be glad;<verse eID="Hab.1.15"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.1.16" sID="Hab.1.16"/>therefore he will sacrifice to his net and burn incense to his dredge. Because by these he made his mess rich and his food delicious,<verse eID="Hab.1.16"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.1.17" sID="Hab.1.17"/>shall he on the account of this cast his dredge, and not spare to slay nations continually?<verse eID="Hab.1.17"/></p><chapter eID="Hab.1"/>
<chapter osisID="Hab.2" sID="Hab.2"/>
<p>
<verse osisID="Hab.2.1" sID="Hab.2.1"/>I will stand on my watch and go up upon a rock and look around, that I may
see what he will say to me and what answer I shall receive to my expostulation.</p>
<p>
<speaker>Jehovah</speaker><verse eID="Hab.2.1"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.2.2" sID="Hab.2.2"/>And the Lord answered and said, Write a vision: write it distinctly in a book that the reader may trace these things;<verse eID="Hab.2.2"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.2.3" sID="Hab.2.3"/>for the vision is for a time yet to come. But it will spring up at last and will not be vain. Though he may tarry, wait for him; for he will assuredly come and will not fail.<verse eID="Hab.2.3"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.2.4" sID="Hab.2.4"/>If any one draw back my soul hath no pleasure in him. But the just shall live by faith in me.<verse eID="Hab.2.4"/></p>
<p>
<verse osisID="Hab.2.5" sID="Hab.2.5"/>Now this arrogant and contemptuous man—this man of boasts shall not exceed a certain bound. He enlarged his soul like Hades and like death was not
satisfied. When he shall have gathered to him all the nations and received for himself all the peoples,<verse eID="Hab.2.5"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.2.6" sID="Hab.2.6"/>will they not all take up a parable against him and a fable to tell of him, saying, Woe to him who is heaping up for himself things which do not belong to him? For how long? And making his yoke grievously heavy.<verse eID="Hab.2.6"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.2.7" sID="Hab.2.7"/>For biters of him shall start up suddenly. And the plotters against thee
shall be sober and thou shalt be plunder for them.<verse eID="Hab.2.7"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.2.8" sID="Hab.2.8"/>Because thou hast plundered many nations, all the remaining peoples shall plunder thee for the blood of mankind, and for the impieties of a land and a city and of all them who inhabit it.<verse eID="Hab.2.8"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.2.9" sID="Hab.2.9"/>Woe to him who coveteth wicked gain for his house, that he<verse eID="Hab.2.9"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.2.10" sID="Hab.2.10"/>may raise his nest high to be out of the reach of evils. Thou hast contrived shame for thy house; thou hast provoked many<verse eID="Hab.2.10"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.2.11" sID="Hab.2.11"/>peoples and thy soul hath sinned; for a stone out of a wall will cry out, and a Worm from a beam will proclaim these things.<verse eID="Hab.2.11"/></p>
<p>
<verse osisID="Hab.2.12" sID="Hab.2.12"/>Woe to him who buildeth a city with blood and furbisheth up a city with iniquities!<verse eID="Hab.2.12"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.2.13" sID="Hab.2.13"/>Are not these things from the Lord Almighty? When many nations have fainted by fire, and many peoples have been dispirited,<verse eID="Hab.2.13"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.2.14" sID="Hab.2.14"/>that the earth may be filled with a knowledge of the glory of God. Like water it will cover them.<verse eID="Hab.2.14"/></p>
<p>
<verse osisID="Hab.2.15" sID="Hab.2.15"/>Woe to him who maketh his neighbour drink a foamy intoxicating draught, making him drunk that he may inspect his caves.<verse eID="Hab.2.15"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.2.16" sID="Hab.2.16"/>Because of thy glory drink thou also a full draught of dishonour, and be confounded at heart and shaken. The cup of the right hand of the Lord is come round to thee and dishonour is heaped upon thy glory.<verse eID="Hab.2.16"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.2.17" sID="Hab.2.17"/>For the impiety at Libanus shall cover thee and the sufferings of wild beasts shall terrify thee, on the account of the blood of mankind, and for the wickedness of a land and a city and of all them who inhabit it.<verse eID="Hab.2.17"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.2.18" sID="Hab.2.18"/>Of what avail is a graven thing, that they have engraved it? Did one cause a molten mass, a false fantasy, to be cast, because the caster had a confidence that by casting he would make dumb idols?<verse eID="Hab.2.18"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.2.19" sID="Hab.2.19"/>Woe to him who saith to Wood, Awake; arise. And to stone, be thou exalted. The one is indeed a fantasy; and the other, a plating of gold and
silver: there is no breath in it.<verse eID="Hab.2.19"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.2.20" sID="Hab.2.20"/>But the Lord is in his holy temple. Let all the earth be awed at his presence.<verse eID="Hab.2.20"/></p><chapter eID="Hab.2"/>
<chapter osisID="Hab.3" sID="Hab.3"/>
<p type="x-embedded">
<verse osisID="Hab.3.1" sID="Hab.3.1"/>The Prayer of Ambacum the prophet; with an Ode.</p>
<p><verse eID="Hab.3.1"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.3.2" sID="Hab.3.2"/>Lord, I have heard the report of thee and am terrified; I have considered thy works and am struck with amaze. In the midst of two living beings thou wilt be known; when the years draw nigh thou wilt be acknowledged; when the time is come thou wilt be pointed out: when my soul is troubled, in wrath remember mercy.<verse eID="Hab.3.2"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.3.3" sID="Hab.3.3"/>God will come from Thaiman, even the Holy One from the thick shady mountains of Pharan.<verse eID="Hab.3.3"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.3.4" sID="Hab.3.4"/>His glory obscured the heavens; and the earth was full of his praise. His
splendor will be like light—beaming rays in his hands, which impressed a lasting love of his majesty.<verse eID="Hab.3.4"/></p>
<p>
<verse osisID="Hab.3.5" sID="Hab.3.5"/>Before him Logos <transChange type="added">the word</transChange> will march, and advance into the plain.<verse eID="Hab.3.5"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.3.6" sID="Hab.3.6"/>He stood and the earth was shaken: he looked, and nations melted away: the mountains were violently convulsed, the everlasting hills melted.<verse eID="Hab.3.6"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.3.7" sID="Hab.3.7"/>Instead of labours I beheld his marches of old. The dwellings of the Ethiopians shall be terrified! And the tents of the land of Madian!<verse eID="Hab.3.7"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.3.8" sID="Hab.3.8"/>Wast thou, Lord, angry with the rivers? Or was thy wrath against the rivers? Or thine indignation against a sea, that thou shouldst mount thy horses? Thy riding is indeed salvation.<verse eID="Hab.3.8"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.3.9" sID="Hab.3.9"/>Thou hast bent thy bow effectually against sceptres. The Lord saith, "The land of rivers shall be broken;<verse eID="Hab.3.9"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.3.10" sID="Hab.3.10"/>peoples shall see and be in pangs." Thou art scattering the rolling waters. The deep roared. It swelled high.<verse eID="Hab.3.10"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.3.11" sID="Hab.3.11"/>The sun was withdrawn: and the moon stood on its orbit. Thy bolts will glance for light, for a glare of the lightening of thine arms.<verse eID="Hab.3.11"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.3.12" sID="Hab.3.12"/>With a threat thou canst diminish a land, and with wrath crush nations.<verse eID="Hab.3.12"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.3.13" sID="Hab.3.13"/>Thou hast marched forth for the salvation of thy people, to save thine anointed One. Thou wilt pour death on the head of transgressors, thou hast raised chains up to the neck.<verse eID="Hab.3.13"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.3.14" sID="Hab.3.14"/>Thou hast struck with consternation the heads of mighties, at this they will be appalled! They will slacken their reins and be like a poor man eating in secret,<verse eID="Hab.3.14"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.3.15" sID="Hab.3.15"/>whilst thou art pressing into the sea thy horses ruffling a mighty water.<verse eID="Hab.3.15"/></p>
<p>
<verse osisID="Hab.3.16" sID="Hab.3.16"/>I watched myself; and at the sound of the prayer of my lips my bowels trembled and a tremor seized my bones; and under me my whole frame quivered. I
shall be at rest in the day of affliction, at the time of his coining to the people of my neighbourhood.<verse eID="Hab.3.16"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.3.17" sID="Hab.3.17"/>Since the fig tree will not flourish, nor will there be fruit on the vines; the product of the olive will fail and the fields will supply no food—For want of food the flocks have failed, and there are no kine in the
stalls;<verse eID="Hab.3.17"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.3.18" sID="Hab.3.18"/>As for me, I will rejoice in the Lord; I shall have joy for God my
saviour.<verse eID="Hab.3.18"/>
<verse osisID="Hab.3.19" sID="Hab.3.19"/>The Lord God is my strength, and will guide my feet to the end. He maketh me walk in high places; that I may triumph with his song.<verse eID="Hab.3.19"/></p><chapter eID="Hab.3"/>
</div>
</osisText>
</osis>
